We are continuously bombarded by
light, photons.
And what's quite amazing is that a part of your brain, which is the retina,
is capable of capturing the smallest
possible particle of light, which is a photon.
The eye, we will see that it has a very high level of...
cerebral activity, it's even an exteriorized brain, it's an expansion
of your brain.
And we will see that this eye will naturally have an importance in the static of
your neck, thus directly influencing your center of gravity.
So the eye influences your center of gravity, and your
center
of gravity influences the eye.
So the eye is actually the beacon
for all the facials.
Eye tensions,
which we see in our consultations,
are often related
to the liver.
Whether it's a red eye or a yellow eye,
they are a hepatic expression.
The heart also, there is an important thing,
it's that already in embryology,
the eye will come to rest
on the heart.
And it will receive
a rhythmic information,
like the throat, that is,
your voice, and like
the hands. Already, the information
from your hands, the information
from your eyes, the information
from your voice are already
electric charges,
magnetic,
electromagnetic.
You work
you work with your eyes.
One can
hypnotize someone, you see,
through the voice. Be careful,
I am warning you.
These frequencies, in fact, because they are electric fields, so the same thing with your hands, same
thing with the eyes. But in fact, what happens is that we modify
alpha frequencies,
you see all these brain frequencies that are also important phenomena of stabilization,
but in fact the eye already receives information from the heart, from the primary heart, from the good heart. Buddhists
say that there is a little invisible thread connecting the heart and
the eyes.
Do this exercise of looking at me with your heart.
Really to create this connection.
To change and look at me like this.
And you will see that something will change in the eye.
There is a geometry.
The geometry of the smile.
These are very subtle geometric changes.
Of looking with the heart.
Because one word, one gesture, one look
can block someone for a lifetime.
But one word, one gesture, one look,
if delivered at the right time,
the right space,
with the right mental image,
can free someone.
But for that, one must have the right timing.
Here, we want to be recognized,
to be able to truly emerge from that.
The same goes for your hands, and the same goes for your voice.
This is about attention, because if we want to work on vision,
we must learn to be attentive.
So attention is a tool we must hone.
The kidneys will modify, through fear, your vision, your perception of
reality.
Fear can completely change it.
It's like anger, you see, boom, I change my reality.
Initially, anger is a force of clarity.
But when anger arises, if you are attentive,
there is clarity.
We see the fault.
The work will be an embryological work, an anatomical work,
a work of functional studies and then a slightly more spiritual work on the eye.
So we will work a little on what we call the differences.
which are important because they will give us what we call the world of perception,
the world of sensation, the world of volition, the world of consciousness.
But learning to gradually make the distinction between possibly
the illusion that may appear.
It's not easy because we quickly develop what we call prejudices.
So here, he is confident.
This means he will undergo his environment, the entirety of his environment.
And in fact, he is there before the bone.
So it will be the soft that controls the hard.
He will have laws, laws of position, laws of mobility, laws of information integration.
And then we will have to also understand this purely neurosensory level of the eye,
this neuromotor pathway that we will study, because we will still study neurophysiology.
We will still get into a bit of detail from the moment we touch
the eye,
when a photon touches the eye, all that will happen.
From your conjunctiva, your cornea, all these fluids it will touch, boom,
and at some point, it will create a transduction.
So it will change this light into electricity.
And then it will go to the lateral geniculate body.
So it will go to a part of your brain
that will be completely influenced throughout the system of pathways,
we will see, and then with the olivary nuclei, the pulvinar, all that will be integrated,
to go towards a radiation in the occipital areas,
which will retransmit another information to us,
that is, we lose 80% of reality.
Already in our way of seeing, that's crazy,
that is, we are heavily influenced by our experiences.
We will lose 80%.
It's almost organized.
We will always be in a mechanism of interpretation.
And as soon as there is emotion, as soon as there are stories lived, we will see things
like that.
And so it will be important gradually to dare to be curious.
And so the goal as an osteopath will be to be able to receive this information,
environmental types as well, because we will not only look at
one thing,
but also this facial level.
So treating the eye means treating the whole body.
But to treat the eye, one must first treat the whole body.
One can say that the eye is like a kind of balance
between a structure in which it has integrated
and the problem that can be expressed.
So it will be a balance.